

Ace Hood

Senior Full Stack BlockChain Engineer

Creative, Passionate, and Efficient Web & Blockchain engineer having 7+ years of experience, adept at all stages of advanced web development. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

acehood010126@gmail.com

+353 086 8458696

Oublin, Ireland

github.com/acehood0126

EDUCATION

Western Governors University (WGU)

2013 - 2015

Bachelor of Computer Science

Courses

- Computer Architecture

- Data Structures and Algorithms I - Data Structures and Algorithms II

- Computer Science Capstone

- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence

TECHNICAL SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Languages: C/C++, Advanced C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Solidity

Frameworks & Libraries: React, Redux, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Express.js, TailwindCSS, web3.js,

styled-components, Laravel, Codelgniter(CI), GraphQL, Apollo

Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase

UI/UX Design: Figma, Webflow, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

Tools: Amazon Web Service(AWS), Google Cloud Platform, Microsoft Azure, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Blockchain Engineer

Self-employed/Freelance

03/2022 - Present

- Responsible for development for a mobile/desktop application that is used by UCI campus bus drivers and administrative staff for scheduling.
- Developed smart contracts for NFT minting, staking, marketplaces & new token.
- Built new React components for the customer facing web application on minenations, improving the average user time on page by 2 minutes.
- Created design concepts and adjusted design elements to address user interface (UI) and user experience (UX).
- Technology: React, Redux, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, TailwindCSS, styled-components, web3.js, MongoDB, Solidity

Lead Front-End & Blockchain Engineer

Cropper Accountancy

Remote California, United States 04/2021 - 02/2022

- Implemented websites, mobile applications and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Developed product tours with Nuxt.js for a new feature, improving customer adoption by 25% leading to increased revenue by \$1M.
- Worked with UX/UI design teams to improve existing applications and increase conversion rate by 20%.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Technology: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, TypeScript, Ant Design, web3.js, Solana, Netlify

Senior Full-Stack Developer

Shmacked

Remote Texas, United States 05/2020 - 03/2021

- Improved functionalities and pipeline integration by designing and implementing cross-platform frameworks.
- Contributed to an ~18% rise in subscribers MoM for 6 months by enhancing the user's experience on all supported client platforms.
- Built extensive test coverage for all new features, reducing the number of customer complaints by 10%.
- Fixed bugs and problems across the entire codebase in an efficient timely manner.
- Technology: React, Lodash, LazySizes, TailwindCSS, Figma, Netlify

Junior Full-Stack Developer

Creativ-Cult GmbH

Remote Hessen, Germany 02/2018 - 03/2020

- Built cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites, resulting in 22% faster load time than industry average.
- Produced multiple visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code,
 producing high quality markup using PHP
- Worked closely with an agile team of 10 members and provided end-to-end solution for clients.
- Technology: PHP, Laravel, Lodash, Bootstrap, MySQL, toastr, jQuery

Front-End Developer

Trackd Music

London, England, United Kingdom 02/2016 - 11/2017

- Ensured end to end process of data extraction until reporting, increased efficiency by up to 25%.
- Built the next version of client web application to add new user designs and features using native
 JavaScript and in-house framework, reducing reported bug issues by over 15%.
- Assisted with writing Vue.js and TypeScript code for applications and software testing.
- Technology: Vue.js, Firebase, Stripe, Lodash, howler.js, TypeScript